<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Choria Configuration Manager</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/index.html</link><description>Overview Mainstream Configuration Management systems focus on full-system management, optimized for 100s or 1000s of managed resources per node. This makes them complex to use and with a lot of dependencies.
Systems like Puppet do not really do well with Application management - they focus on on systems management.
Choria has Autonomous Agents that can be used for application lifecycle management but thus far lacked any kind of Configuration Management.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/resources/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/resources/index.html</guid><description>A resource is how you describe the desired state of your infrastructure. They represent a thing you want to manage and they are backed by providers which implement the actual management for your Operating System.
Each resource has a type and a unique name followed by some resource-specific properties.
Common Properties Resources can all have additional monitoring / health checks associated with them. See the Monitoring page for more information.</description></item><item><title>Data</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/data/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/data/index.html</guid><description>Just like applications need data to vary their behavior and configure their environments, so do Configuration Management tools.
For this reason I wrote extlookup and hiera years ago for the Puppet community. Despite the minimal focus of this tool we still need data to vary the behaviour.
Data can be used for:
Configuring resource names that differ between Operating Systems like httpd vs apache2 package names Set different configuration values depending on environment, role or other dimensions Decide if some environments shold have something installed and others not - like development vs production environments Choria CM supports various data sources:</description></item><item><title>CLI Usage</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/cli/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/cli/index.html</guid><description>We are designing CCM to be used as a CLI tool as its first class method of interaction.
Each resource type has its own subcommand under ccm ensure that maps to the resource type, with required inputs being arguments and optionals being flags.
The CLI commands are designed to be idempotent; this means that they can be used to write shell scripts that can safely be run multiple times.
Managing a single resource Managing a single resource is really easy, however, some features will not function without preparing a session.</description></item><item><title>YAML Manifests</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/yamlmanifests/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/yamlmanifests/index.html</guid><description>A manifest is a YAML file that combines data, platform-specific configuration and resources all in one file.
There is no logic - other than what expressions can do, consider it to be no more complex than basic example multi-resource shell scripts.
The YAML file resolves the manifest using Choria Hierarchical Data Resolver, our single-file implementation of Hiera.
Full Example Input Data First, we define input data, think of this like the properties a module accepts:</description></item><item><title>Monitoring</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/monitoring/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/ccm/monitoring/index.html</guid><description>Resources will check their health in the basic way that resources support - if you say a service should be running, if systemd says it’s running then we assume it’s healthy.
In some cases, though, it makes sense to go deeper than that, for example check the web server is actually serving correct content.
All resources support health checks.
service: name: httpd ensure: running enable: true subscribe: package#zsh health_check: tries: 5 try_sleep: 1s command: | /usr/lib64/nagios/plugins/check_http -H localhost:80 --expect "Acme Inc" Here we check that the web server is serving the correct content - the output must include Acme Inc. If at first it is not doing that we will try again every 1 second for five times.</description></item></channel></rss>