<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Package Type :: Choria Configuration Manager</title><link>https://choria-cm.dev/design/package/index.html</link><description>This document describes the design of the package resource type for managing software packages.
Overview The package resource manages software packages with two aspects:
Existence: Whether the package is installed or absent Version: The specific version installed (when applicable) Provider Interface Package providers must implement the PackageProvider interface:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://choria-cm.dev/design/package/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>APT Provider</title><link>https://choria-cm.dev/design/package/apt/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-cm.dev/design/package/apt/index.html</guid><description>This document describes the implementation details of the APT package provider for Debian-based systems.
Environment All commands are executed with the following environment variables to ensure non-interactive operation:
Variable Value Purpose DEBIAN_FRONTEND noninteractive Prevents dpkg from prompting for user input APT_LISTBUGS_FRONTEND none Suppresses apt-listbugs prompts APT_LISTCHANGES_FRONTEND none Suppresses apt-listchanges prompts Concurrency A global package lock (model.PackageGlobalLock) is held during all command executions to prevent concurrent apt/dpkg operations within the same process. This prevents lock contention on /var/lib/dpkg/lock.</description></item><item><title>DNF Provider</title><link>https://choria-cm.dev/design/package/dnf/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-cm.dev/design/package/dnf/index.html</guid><description>This document describes the implementation details of the DNF package provider for RHEL/Fedora-based systems.
Concurrency A global package lock (model.PackageGlobalLock) is held during all command executions to prevent concurrent dnf/rpm operations within the same process. This prevents lock contention on the RPM database.
Operations Status Check Command:</description></item></channel></rss>